Guide to the The Inquiry Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Reports and Studies, 1917-1920, undated; Series III
  - Paraguay, the Chaco
    - "The Paraguan Chaco." By F. B. Morris. 18 pp., 1918 August (Box 16, Folder 245)
      Maps and photographs.
  - Peace Terms
    - "Memorandum. A Suggested Statement of Peace Terms." [no author] 69 pp., 1918 January 2 (Box 16, Folder 246)
      Revised and enlarged from Part III of the Memorandum of 1917 Dec 22.
  - Persia
    See also: box 10, folder 127-128.
    - "Preliminary Report on Persia." By A.V. Williams Jackson. 68 pp., 1918 February 1 (Box 16, Folder 247)
      Tables in photostat.
    - "Persia: Delimitation of the Present Frontiers." By A. V. Williams Jackson. 8 pp., received 1918 April 30 (Box 16, Folder 248)
    - "Education - The Need of Greater Educational Opportunities in Persia." By A. V. Williams Jackson. 15 pp., Received 1918 March 30 (Box 17, Folder 249)
  - Peru
    - "Peru: Outline Study of Existing Conditions." [no author] 20 pp., Undated (Box 17, Folder 250)
    - "Outline of Peru (revised from that prepared in State Department)." By Osgood Hardy. 18 pp., 1918 June 22 (Box 17, Folder 250a)
  - Petrograd Protocol
    - "Protocol of Petrograd, May 10, 1913." By W. S. Monroe. 3 pp., 1918 April 4 (Box 17, Folder 251)
  - Poland
    See also: box 24, folder 376.
    - "Report on Poland." By R. H. Lord. 147 pp., 1918 January 21 (Box 17, Folder 252)
    - "Joint Report on Poland." By H. Arctowski. 30 pp., 1918 November 1 (Box 17, Folder 253)
    - "Preliminary Report on Poland." By Henryk Arctowski. 106 pp., 1918 January 31 (Box 17, Folder 254)
      Second copy revised.
    - "Poland's Access to the Sea." By S. J. Zowski. 90 pp., 1918 November 8 (Box 17, Folder 255)
    - "The Northeastern Boundary of Poland." By R. H. Lord. 33 pp., 1918 March 10 (Box 17, Folder 256)
    - "Poland: Commerce." By Clive Day. 27 pp., 1918 April 17 (Box 17, Folder 256)
    - "The Polish-Ukrainian Boundary." By R. H. Lord. 30 pp., Received 1918 February 18 (Box 17, Folder 258)
      Superceded by a later report.
    - "The New Polish-Ukrainian Boundary as Defined by theTreaty of Brest-Litovsk of February 9, 1918." By R. H. Lord. 35 pp., 1918 February 16 (Box 17, Folder 259)
    - "Statistical Data on Poland. Section II: Agriculture: Parts XVII-XXVI: The Principal Crops, 1908-1912." By H. Arctowski et al. 193 pp. [and 13 paper canvass maps], 1918 July 1 (Box 17, Folder 260)
    - "Statistical Data on Poland. Section III: Farm Animals." By H. Arctowski. 24 pp., 1918 August 29 (Box 17, Folder 261)
    - "Statistical Data on Poland. Section IV: Industry, Prussian Data 1904." By H. Arctowski and L. Jezioranski. 251 pp., 1918 December 18 (Box 17, Folder 262)
    - "Statistical Data on Poland: Industry - Russian Data 1910." By H. Arctowski and L. Jezioranski. 340 pp., 1918 December 10 (Box 18, Folder 263)
    - "The Four Dumas: Poles Elected in the Nine Western Governments." By H. Arctowski. 8 pp., 1918 November 18 (Box 18, Folder 264)
    - "Poland, Economic Production." By S. J. Zowski. 49 pp., 1918 February 26 (Box 18, Folder 265)
    - "The Problem of Eastern Galicia." By R. H. Lord. 101 pp., 1918 April 23 (Box 18, Folder 266)
    - Poland, Ethnography miscellanea. By H. Arctowski. 33 pp., 1918 October 28 (Box 18, Folder 267)
    - "Poland, Industry." By H. Arctowski and L. Jezioranski. 222 pp., 1918 December 14 (Box 18, Folder 268)
    - "Geographical and Statistical Atlas of Poland." Edited by E. Romer. 73 pp., Received 1918 April 25 (Box 18, Folder 269)
    - "Poland and Lithuania." By A. H. Putney. 40 pp., 1918 April 25 (Box 18, Folder 270)
    - "The Experiences of the Last Century in Poland in Regard to the Protection of Minority Peoples." By R. H. Lord. 26 pp., 1918 May 11 (Box 18, Folder 271)
    - "Poland - Economic Factors." [no author] 3 pp., Undated (Box 18, Folder 272)
    - "Poland: Economic and Engineering Problems." By H. Arctowski. 45 pp., 1918 February 28 (Box 18, Folder 273)
      Outsize tables.
    - "Considerations Which would Tend to Draw Poland Toward or Repel Her From Germany, Russia, Austria, in Connection with Her Aspiriations for Independence and Cultural Development." By F. Znaniecki. 5 pp., Received 1918 January 29 (Box 18, Folder 274)
    - "The Organization of Polish Society for Cultural Productivity." By F. Znaniecki. 37 pp., 1918 January 21 (Box 18, Folder 275)
    - "The Political Parties in Poland." By S. J. Zowski. 56 pp., 1918 June 22 (Box 18, Folder 276)
    - "Religious and Linguistic Data for the Nine Western Governments - 1910." By H. Arctowski. 8 pp., 1918 November 28 (Box 18, Folder 277)
      With covering letter to Isaiah Bowman.
    - "Restrictions and Restraints Imposed on the Cultural Development of Poland by Germany, Russia, and Austria." By F. Znaniecki. 39 pp., Received 1918 January 29 (Box 18, Folder 278)
    - "Statistical Data on Bukowina." By Henryk Arctowski. J73 pp., 1918 July 31 (Box 19, Folder 279)
    - "Statistical Data on Poland: Section I: Demography." By H. Arctowski et al. 515 pp., 1918 April 20 (Box 19, Folder 280)
    - "Poland: The Railroads in the Congress Kingdom (Their Present State and Desirable Expansion)." By S. J. Zowski. 14 pp., 1918 March 14 (Box 19, Folder 281)
    - "A Comparative Study of the Various Solutions of the Polish Question." By R. H. Lord. 79 pp., 1918 March 9 (Box 19, Folder 282)
    - "Poland: Alternative Territorial Plans. Economic Conditions: Production, Imports, Exports." By S. J. Zowski. 102 pp., 1918 November 1 (Box 19, Folder 283)
  - Prussia -School Laws and Administration
    - "Prussian School Laws and Administration." By P. Monroe. 71 pp., Undated (Box 19, Folder 284)
  - Public Debts
    - "Report upon the Public Debts of the Principal Countries." By F. R. Fairchild. 225 pp., 1919 January (Box 19, Folder 285)
      Volume I: Allied Powers.
    - "Report upon the Public Debts of the Principal Countries." By F. R. Fairchild. 175 pp., 1919 January (Box 19, Folder 286)
      Volume II: Enemy and Neutral Powers.
  - Raw Materials
    - "The Distribution of Raw Materials: Nickel." [no author] 29 pp., Undated (Box 20, Folder 287)
    - "The Distribution of Raw Materials: Oil Producing Nuts and Seeds." [no author] 110 pp., Undated (Box 20, Folder 288)
  - Rivers: As International Boundaries
    - "Rivers as International Boundaries." By W. H. Hobbs. 108 pp., 1918 February 1 (Box 20, Folder 289)
  - Rumania
    - "Notes on the Dobrudja Boundaries." By W. H. Reed. 3 pp., Undated (Box 20, Folder 290)
    - "The Rumanian People." By W. H. Reed. 95 pp., 1918 November 30 (Box 20, Folder 291)
    - "Memorandum on the Geographic and Strategic Character of the New Frontier Imposed on Roumania by the Treaty of Bucharest." By D. Johnson. 8 pp., Received 1918 July 27 (Box 20, Folder 292)
    - "The Bucharest Treaty as Affecting Rumanian Petroleum Resources." [no author] 8 pp., Undated (Box 20, Folder 293)
  - Russia
    See also:box 4, folder 1.
    See also: box 8, folder 93.
    See also: box 10, folder 129.
    See also: box 11, folder 141.
    See also: box 11, folder 143.
    See also: box 21, folder 308.
    See also: box 24, folder 372-374.
    - "Statistics of Crops in the Russian Empire [Part I]." By I. M. Rubinow. 56 pp., 1918 October (Box 20, Folder 294)
    - "Agricultural Crops in Russia By Provinces [Part II]." By I. M. Rubinow. 48 pp., Undated (Box 20, Folder 295)
    - "Historical Note on the Russian Cessions in Asia Demanded by Germany." By P. W. Slosson. 3 pp., Received 1918 March 8 (Box 21, Folder 296)
    - "Russian Commercial Relations." By Clive Day. 98 pp., 1918 May 28 (Box 21, Folder 297)
    - "Russian Education." By P. Monroe and D. P. Leary et al. 137 pp. [maps], Undated (Box 21, Folder 298)
    - "Statistics of Manufacturing Industries in European Russia." By I. M. Rubinow. 215 pp., 1918 October (Box 21, Folder 299)
    - "The Russo-Japanese Agreement of 1916." By S. K. Hornbeck. 31 pp., Undated (Box 21, Folder 300)
    - "Memorandum: 'New Governments Established in Russia During the War.'" By M. Jefferson [?]. 31 pp.], 1918 November 1 (Box 21, Folder 301)
      Addendum at end.
    - "The Races of Russia." By A. Hrdlicka. 39 pp., Received 1918 July 23 (Box 21, Folder 302)
    - "The Kirgiz-Kazak and the Steppe Region of Western Siberia." By R. B. Dixon. 100 pp., 1918 August 8 (Box 21, Folder 303)
    - "The Situation in Russia." [no author] 2 pp., 1918 December 1 (Box 21, Folder 304)
  - Saloniki
    - "Saloniki - A Natural Outlet for Serbia." By L. Dominian. 1 p., Undated (Box 21, Folder 305)
  - Samoa
    - "The Diplomatic History of the Kingdom of Samoa." By P. W. Slosson. 79 pp., 1918 October (Box 21, Folder 306)
  - Serbia
    See: box 24, folder 377.
  - Siam
    - "Siam: Legal Status of Foreigners." By S. Hornbeck. 2 pp., Undated (Box 21, Folder 306)
  - Siberia
    - "Siberia." By F. A. Golder. 184 pp., 1918 May 25 (Box 21, Folder 308)
  - Slesvig
    - "The Slesvig Problem: The Vitality of Danism in Slesvig." By H. A. Larsen. 16 pp. [maps], Undated (Box 21, Folder 309)
    - "North Schleswig." By L. D. Steefel. 107 pp., 1918 July 25 (Box 21, Folder 310)
    - "The Question of South Jutland." [no author] 19 pp., 1918? March 18 (Box 21, Folder 311)
  - South Africa
    - Six Reports on "Economic Conditions and Industrial Changes in South Africa." By G. Murphy [Consul-General, Cape Town], J. Dye [Consul, Port Elizabeth], W. W. Masterson [Consul, Durban, Natal], S. N. Honaker [Consul, Johannesburg]. 117 pp., 1918 June (Box 21, Folder 312)
      Includes newspaper clippings]\.
  - South and East Africa
    - "South and East Africa." By I. C. Hannah. 21 pp., Received 1918 February 13 (Box 21, Folder 313)
  - South Eastern Europe
    - "Outline for Statistical Abstracts of Southeastern Europe." [no author] 5 pp., 1918 August 14 (Box 21, Folder 314)
      Rough draft in manuscript notes.
  - Spain
    - "The International Position of Spain During the War and in Conferences Following the Peace that is to be Won." By W. M. Collier. 162 pp., Received 1918 August 1 (Box 21, Folder 315)
      Also 5 page commentary in memorandum to Sidney E. Mezes from P. T. Moon.
  - Spitsbergen
    - "Spitsbergen and Bear Island." By L. H. Gray. 134 pp., Received 1918 October 29 (Box 21, Folder 316)
      Text of Protocol of 1912 missing.
    - "The Political Status of Spitsbergen." By Charles Seymour. 4 pp., Received 1918 April 6 (Box 21, Folder 317)
  - States Less Than Sovereign
    - "States Less Than Sovereign." By W. W. Willoughby and C. G. Fenwick. 150 pp., 1918 March 16 (Box 21, Folder 318)
      Includes 4 printed appendices - public documents.
  - Syria
    - "Report on the Desires of the Syrians." By E.H Byrne. 122 pp., 1918 October 7 (Box 22, Folder 319)
      Appendices in photostat.
    - "Report on the Resources of Southern Syria." By D. Magie. 96 pp., 1918 May 6 (Box 22, Folder 320)
  - Tatars
    See: box 10, folder 129.
  - Tibet
    - "Tibet and the Tibetan Marches." By N. D. Harris 21 pp., Undated (Box 22, Folder 321)
  - Transcaucasia
    - "Ceded Territories in the Transcaucasus." By A. I. Andrews. 46 pp. [and addendum], 1918 March 11 (Box 22, Folder 322)
  - Turkestan
    - "Eastern Turkestan." By R. B. Dixon. 62 pp., 1918 September 7 (Box 22, Folder 323)
    - "Western or Russian Turkestan." By R. B. Dixon. 26 pp., 1918 March 8 (Box 22, Folder 324)
    - "Russian or Western Turkestan: Economic Study." By R. B. Dixon. 15 pp., Received 1918 April (Box 22, Folder 325)
  - Turkey
    - "Turkey." By L.Dominian. 126 pp., 1918 January 31 (Box 22, Folder 326)
    - "Report on American Interests in Turkey." By O. J. Campbell. 96 pp., Undated (Box 22, Folder 327)
    - "American Interests in Turkey." By H. C. Butler. 9 pp., Undated (Box 22, Folder 328)
    - "Report on British Interest in Asiatic Turkey." By H. R. Shipman. 36 pp., 1918 April 3 (Box 22, Folder 329)
    - "British Interests in Asiatic Turkey." By J. M. Vincent. 42 pp., Undated (Box 22, Folder 330)
      Addenda: statistics in photostat and map.
    - "The Christian Sects of the Turkish Empire." By D. Magie. 194 pp., Received 1918(?) February 15 (Box 22, Folder 331)
    - Memorandum from L. Dominion to Isaiah Bowman on "Division of Turkey." 2 pp., 1917 December 31 (Box 22, Folder 332)
    - "General Memorandum on Constantinople and the Straits." By A. L. P. Dennis. 21 pp., 1918 February 1 (Box 22, Folder 333)
    - "Trade of Constantinople and the Straits." By W. S. Monroe. 28 pp., 1918 November 27 (Box 22, Folder 334)
    - "Ottoman Empire: Diplomatic Relations with the United States Regarding Education (1830-1916)." By P. Monroe. 110 pp., Undated (Box 22, Folder 335)
    - "Turkey as an Economic Asset to the Central Powers." By J. C. Bonright. 21 pp., Received 1918 March 11 (Box 22, Folder 336)
    - "The Ottoman Empire. Education." By P. Monroe. 124 pp. [maps], Undated (Box 23, Folder 337)
    - "French Interests in Asiatic Turkey." By J. M. Vincent(?) 39 pp., Undated (Box 23, Folder 338)
      Voluminous appendices, statistics in photostat and map.
    - "The Future of Turkey." By H. N. Brailsford. 15 pp., 1918 February (Box 23, Folder 339)
    - "The Turkish Government." By D. C. Munro. 14 pp, Received 1918 January 29 (Box 23, Folder 340)
    - "The Government of Turkey." By W. L. Westermann. 165 pp., 1918 November 15 (Box 23, Folder 341)
    - "The Working of the Turkish Government." By W. W. Peet. 3 pp., Undated (Box 23, Folder 342)
      Includes covering note by J. T. Shotwell.
    - "Outline of the History and Ethnology of the Turkish Empire." By H. Porter. Edited by D. C. Munro. 14 pp., Received 1918 February 20 (Box 23, Folder 343)
    - "Historical Sketch of the Turkish Empire." By W. L. Westermann. 13 pp., Undated (Box 23, Folder 344)
    - "Turkey: Internal Administration. Laws of the Vilayets." By W. L. Westermann. 18 pp., Undated (Box 23, Folder 345)
    - "Report on Italian Ambitions in Asia Minor." By E. H. Byrne. 39 pp., 1918 April 18 (Box 23, Folder 346)
    - "The Kurds of the Ottoman Empire." By D. Magie. 115 pp., Received 1918(?) February (Box 23, Folder 347)
    - "The Lebanon Province." [no author] 5 pp., Undated (Box 23, Folder 348)
    - "Suggestions for the Internationalization of the Historic Monuments of the Nearer East." By J. A. Breasted (?). 5 pp. (Box 23, Folder 349)
    - "The Partition of Asiatic Turkey." By E. C. Semple. 90 pp., 1918 April 30 (Box 23, Folder 350)
    - "An Abridgement of The Partition of Asiatic Turkey by E. C. Semple." By C. S. Brooks. 11 pp., Received 1918 June 17 (Box 23, Folder 351)
    - The Greek Patriarchate of Constantinople: Its History, and Its Functions in the Ottoman State." By H. W. Bell. 25 pp., 1918 August 23 (Box 23, Folder 352)
    - "Population of Asiatic Turkey." By D. Magie(?). 14 pp., Undated (Box 23, Folder 353)
      Appendices I and II of larger study.
    - "Reclamation by Irrigation, Drainage and Flood Protection in Asiatic Turkey." By F. H. Newell, E. C. Semple and W. H. Hobbs. 262 pp., 1918 June (Box 23, Folder 354)
    - "Religious Conditions in the Turkish Empire." By H. Porter. Edited by D. C. Munro. 11 pp., Received 1918 February 20 (Box 23, Folder 355)
    - "Religions in Turkey." [no author] 65 pp., undated (Box 23, Folder 356)
    - "The Independent Sandjak of Karassi." By S. O. Dickerman. 29 pp., Undated (Box 23, Folder 357)
    - "Turkey in Asia, Social Science Data." By D. C. Munro. 8 pp., Undated (Box 24, Folder 358)
    - "Solutions to Problems in Asiatic Turkey." By J. T. Shotwell et al. 4 pp., Undated (Box 24, Folder 359)
      Appended memoranda missing.
    - "The Proposed International State at the Straits." By H. W. Bell. 37 pp., 1918 (Box 24, Folder 360)
      2 reports.
    - "Turkish Survey. Harpoot District." By H. W. Riggs. Edited by W. H. Hall. 20 pp., Received 1918 January 25 (Box 24, Folder 361)
    - "Turkish Survey: The Ottoman Turks of Asia Minor." By J. K. Birge. 12 pp. [photostats] (Box 24, Folder 362)
    - Turkish Survey: The Kurds." By A. N. Andrus. Edited by D. C. Munro. 13 pp., Received 1918 February 20 (Box 24, Folder "363)
    - "Turkish Survey: The Kurds." By H. H. Riggs. Edited by W. H. Hall. 5 pp., Undated (Box 24, Folder 364)
    - "Turkish Survey: Petroleum." Edited by W. H. Hall. 2 pp., Received 1918 January 23 (Box 24, Folder 365)
    - "Turkish Survey: Rug Industry." By G. Gulbenkian. Edited by W. H. Hall. 5 pp., Received 1918 January 29 (Box 24, Folder 366)
    - "Report on the Vilayet of Aidin." By O. J. Campbell. 62 pp., Undated (Box 24, Folder 367)
    - "Report on the Vilayet of Aleppo." By D. Magie. 48 pp., Undated (Box 24, Folder 368)
    - "Report of the Vilayet of Hudavendighiar." By S. O. Dickerman. 38 pp., Undated (Box 24, Folder 369)
    - "Report on the Vilayet of Konia." By O. J. Campbell. 26 pp., Undated (Box 24, Folder 370)
      Statistical tables, one in photostat.
    - "Report on the Vilayet of Sivas." By J. N. Beam. [received Feb. 11, 1919.] 38 pp., Received 1919 February 11 (Box 24, Folder 371)
  - Ukraine
    - "Ukraine." By F. A. Golder. 185 pp., 1918 November 1 (Box 24, Folder 372)
    - "Ukraine." By F. A. Golder. 111 pp., 1918 February 15 (Box 24, Folder 373)
      Maps and tables in photostat.
    - "Economic Relations Between Ukraine and European Russia." By I. M. Rubinow. 57 pp., 1918 October (Box 24, Folder 374)
  - United States Commercial Policy
    - "Memorandum on the Policy to be Followed by the United States in International Negotiations on Commercial Policy." By F. W. Taussig. 2 pp., Undated (Box 24, Folder 375)
  - Uruguay
    - "Outline Study of Existing Conditions: Uruaguay." [no author] 21 pp., 1919 (Box 24, Folder 375a)
  - Venezuela Boundary Dispute
    See:box 10, folder 124-126.
  - Venezuela
    - "Outline Study of Existing Conditions: Venezuela." [no author] 25 pp., 1919 (Box 24, Folder 375b)
  - Vistula River
    - "The Vistula River as a Commercial Highway." By S. J. Zowski. 23 pp., 1918 January 30 (Box 24, Folder 376)
  - Yugoslavia
    - "List of important documents illustrating the Jugo-Slav problem, 1527-1918." By Robert J. Kerner. 7 pp., Undated (Box 24, Folder 377)
    - "The Movement for Freedom and Unity of the Jugoslays (Serbs, Croats, and Slovenes)." By V. R. Savic. 35 pp. [map], Received 1918 February 21 (Box 24, Folder 378)
    - "Memorandum. A brief sketch of the political movements among the Jugo-Slavs toward the federalization or dismemberment of Austria-Hungary." By Robert J. Kerner. 100 pp., 1918 March 25 (Box 24, Folder 379)
      Also 15-page resume, 1918 June 12, tables and maps in photostat.
    - "Obscurity Regarding the Istrian Islands." [no author] 1 p., Undated (Box 24, Folder 380)
    - "The Serbo-Bulgarian Frontier." By A. H. Lybyer. 66 pp., 1918 November 1 (Box 24, Folder 381)
    - "Projected Serbian Railways to the Adriatic." By W.S. Monroe. 14 pp., 1918 October 30 (Box 24, Folder 382)
    - "Territories in Austria-Hungary claimed by the Jugoslays Statistical Study." By Charles Seymour. 66 pp., 1918 April 1 (Box 24, Folder 383)
    - "Austria-Hungary: Jugo-Slav Trialism." By Charles Seymour. 5 pp., 1918 May 25 (Box 24, Folder 384)
  - Zionism
    - "A Report on Zionism." By O. J. Campbell. 232 pp., Received 1918 August 23 (Box 24, Folder 385)
- Abstracts, Precis, Notes, 1902-1918, undated; Series IV
  Series IV contains material compiled by (or for) individual Inquiry staff members (primarily Charles Seymour and Clive Day) as aids in preparation of some of the Reports found in Series III.
  Series IV has been subdivided into four main categories, with entries arranged alphabetically within each category: (a) Miscellaneous Statistical Tables; (b) Abstracts of Miscellaneous Area Studies; (c) Miscellaneous Research Notes; (d) Abstracts, Precis, Translations (of articles, speeches, etc., drawn from outside sources).
  - Miscellaneous Statistical Tables
    - Adriatic Ports
      - "Austria-Hungary: Annual Average Trade of Adriatic Ports 1906-1907." [and memorandum in manuscript] (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - "Movement of Navigation at the Principal Adriatic Ports." From: "Movimento della Navigazione del Regno d'Italia anno 1910." Vol. I [manuscript] (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Alsace-Lorraine: "The Value of Alsace-Lorraine to Germany." Compiled by E. Krehbiel. (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Austria-Hungary
      - "Chief Crops of Austria by Natural Regions." (Box 25, Folder 3)
      - Economic Statistics., Received 1918 March 11 (Box 25, Folder 4)
      - "The Jugo-Slavs in Austria: Bosnia-Herzegovina." Statistical Abstract. By Charles Seymour., Received 1918 April 8 (Box 25, Folder 5)
      - Miscellaneous economic statistics. (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - China: Population statistics on China., Received 1918 August 7 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Eastern Europe: Statistics on crop production for various countries of Eastern Europe. (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Food Production: Statistics on food production in different countries of the world. Average for years 1910-1914. (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - German Empire: Economic Statistics on the German Empire., Received 1918 March 11 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Italy
      - "Special Trade between Italy and Other Countries - 1910." From: Annuario Statistico Italiano, Vol. I, pp. 150-151., 1911 (Box 25, Folder 11)
      - "Movement of navigation at the principal ports for 1910." (op. cit. p. 175), 1911 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Korea: Statistical Tables. (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Pacific Islands: Economic Statistics. By A. P. Winston. (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Poland: "Discussion of Statistical Data. Appendixes [sic] I-19." Compiled by H. Arctowski., 1918 August 20 (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Russia: "Tables Relating to Land Ownership (1905)." By I. M. Rubinow., Received 1918 October 2 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Abstracts of Miscellaneous Area Studies
    - Austria-Hungary: "Natural Regions of Austria." From: Statistisches Jahrbuch des Ackerbau-Ministeriums, 1913, Wien. pp. 19-25., 1914 (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Brest-Litovsk: Texts, Appendices, and Summaries of the Treaty of Brest-Litovsk. United States Department of State (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - China: "Tentative Chronoligical List of Treaties, Conventions, Contracts and Other Agreements With or Concerning China, Relative to Railways, Concluded Between the Years 1894 and 1917." Compiled from List of Treaties Prepared by Mac Murray, First Secretary, American Legation, Peking., 1917 December 26 (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - Dutch East Indies: "Memorandum on the Dutch East Indies." United States War Trade Board., Undated (Box 25, Folder 19)
    - Forests: "Forest Resources of the World." United States Forest Service, United States Department of Agriculture., 1918 November 30 (Box 25, Folder 20)
    - European Private International Investment: Bibliography on private European international investment. Library of Congress., 1918 May 2 (Box 26, Folder 21)
    - Latin America
      - "Annual Report of Venezuelan Treasury." By H. Brett, Consul La Guaira, in Commerce Reports, United States Department of Commerce. Memorandum on Bolivian Finances., 1918 May 9 (Box 26, Folder 22)
      - "Catalogue of Bureau Publications." Bureau of Foreign and Domestic Commerce, United States Department of Commerce. March 15, 1918., 1918 March 15 (Box 26, Folder 22)
    - Morocco: "Phosphate Rock Deposits in Morocco. "By J. C. Martin, United States Geological Survey, United States Department of the Interior. (Box 26, Folder 23)
    - Russia
      - "The Forests of Asiatic Russia." Forest Service, United States Department of Agriculture. Sept. 17, 1918., 1918 September 17 (Box 26, Folder 24)
      - "Letter from G. B. Rea to E. T. Williams in Regard to the Russo-Japanese Alliance." United States Department of State., 1915 August 1 (Box 26, Folder 25)
    - Spitzbergen: "Spitzbergen, Geography and Economic Conditions." (Box 26, Folder 26)